### Curriculum Vitae – Prince Kobina Sakyi

#### **Personal Details**

Name	Prince Kobina Sakyi
Date of Birth	16 <sup>th</sup> September, 1997
Nationality	Ghana
Physical Address	Osuown Street, New Fadama-Accra
Personal Website	http://prince-sakyi.github.io
Email	princesakyikobina@gmail.com
Telephone	0556794517

#### **Profile Summary**

Prince Sakyi is a highly motivated, adaptable, diligent and a versatile person who possesses the drive to constantly build capacity. In the last four years, apart from obtaining his first degree, he has continuously taken online courses to broaden the scope of his knowledge. His ability to take initiative is evidenced in his personal motivation to progressively take courses to augment his university training and to enhance his career in finance. His internship experiences have exposed him to the corporate environment and equipped him with exceptional work ethics.

#### **Objective**

\* To become an expert in Financial Data Analysis and Payroll Accounting.

**Education/Professional Training** 

Name of institution	Programme	Year
University of Cape Coast	Bachelor of Commerce (Accounting)	October, 2020
Association of Chartered	Level 2	December, 2020
Certified Accountants (ACCA)		
Institute of Chartered	Level 2	January 2021
Accountants Ghana (ICAG)		

#### **Language Proficiency**

Language	Speaking	Reading	Writing
English	Good	Good	Good
Twi	Good	Good	Fair
Hausa	Good	Fair	Fair

#### **Work Experience**

Name of Organisation	Ga Central Municipal Assembly	
Year	September 2020 to date	
Location	Accra, Ghana	
Position held	National Service Person	
Key Responsibilities	Prepared weekly and monthly revenue returns	
	Reconciled Zonal account on monthly basis	
	Prepared yearly revenue and expenditure returns	

Name of organisation	Absa Bank
Year	June 2019 -August 2019
Location	Accra, Ghana
Position held	Intern
Key Responsibilities	•Auditing treasury ins and outs
	Auditing ATM forms
	Verifying ATM reconciliations
	Customer care call services
	Accounts opening reconciliations

Name of organisation	Ga Central Municipal Assembly	
Year	September 2018 -August 2018	
Location	Accra, Ghana	
Position held	Intern	
Key Responsibilities	Prepared weekly and monthly revenue and expenditure accounts	
	Assisted in the preparation of memos for zonal meetings	
	Reconciliation of yearly accounts	

## **Voluntary Work**

Name of organisation	Oda Senior High School
Year	January 2018
Location	Akim-Oda, Ghana
Key Responsibility	Prepared final year students for WASSCE examination

Name of organisation	Grace Foundation International School
Year	May 2017 -August 2017
Location	Accra, Ghana
Key Responsibilities	Prepared lesson notes for effective teaching as well as helped new
	recruits to prepare their lesson notes
	Set examination questions and typed them appropriately
	Conducted quizzes and debates
	Trained students for inter-school competitions

# **Progressive Personal Development (MOOCs)**

Course	Excel Skills for Business
Awarding Institution	Macquarie University
Year	March 2021

Skills Obtained	•Data Visualization
	• Pivot Chart

Course	Data Visualization with Advanced Excel
Awarding Institution	PwC
Year	January 2021
Skills Obtained	Dashboard (Business)
	Data Visualization

Course	Data-Driven Decision Making
Awarding Institution	PwC
Year	January 2021
Skills Obtained	Data Analysis
	• Big Data
	Data Visualization
	Data Informed Decision Making

Course	The Art of Negotiation
Awarding Institution	University of California
Year	August 2020
Skills Obtained	Principled Negotiation
	Win-Win Game
	• Planning
	Negotiation

Course	Problem Solving with Excel
Awarding Institution	PwC
Year	June 2019
Skills Obtained	Data Analysis
	• Pivot Table
	Data Cleansing
	Microsoft Excel

Course	Introduction to Corporate Finance
Awarding Institution	Corporate Finance Institute
Year	May 2019
Skills Obtained	Capital Financing
	Capital Investment
	Dividend policies

Course	Effective Communication
Awarding Institution	The Open University
Year	April 2020
Skills Obtained	Conducting productive meetings
	Writing professional reports and proposals
	Effective phone calls and emails
	Delivering effective presentations

Course	Excel Crash Course
--------	--------------------

Awarding Institution	Corporate Finance Institute
Year	April 2020
Skills Obtained	Advanced Financial Analysis Setup
	Basic Financial Analysis Setup
	Excel layout

Course	Accounting Fundamentals
Awarding Institution	Corporate Finance Institute
Year	April 2020
Skills Obtained	Constructing a cash flow statement
	Constructing a balance sheet
	Constructing an income statement

Course	Financial, Work, Money & People Skills
Awarding Institution	Absa
Year	April 2019
Skills Obtained	Money skills
	People skills
	Work skills
	Entrepreneurial skills

Course	Reading Financial Statements
Awarding Institution	Corporate Finance Institute
Year	April 2019
Skills Obtained	Understanding financial statements
	Interpreting financial statement figures

Course	Microsoft Office
Awarding Institution	Alison
Year	November 2016
Skills Obtained	Power Point
	Access & Outlook
	• Word
	• Excel

## **Professional Affiliations**

- \* Student Member, Association of Chartered Certified Accountants
- \* Student Member, Institute of Chartered Accountants

### Referees

Ms. Sarah Nana Akua Asare Manager Absa Bank

0244896564

Enock Gyan

Senior Associate, Communications

The Palladium Group

0542731844